Guide to the Horticultural Society of New York Records 1811-circa 2010 (bulk, 1900-circa 2010) MS 3033
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI. Print Matter, 1811-circa 2010; 213348; 22.19 Linear feet
  - Subseries VI.C. Miscellaneous Print Material, 1811-1997; 212854; 7.25 Linear feet
    - Seed Catalog: Burpee's Annual (Philadelphia: W. Atlee Burpee & Co.), 1919; 212889 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 5)
    - Seed Catalog (Gregory): Annual Circular and Retail Catalogue of Warranted Vegetable and Flower Seeds (Marblehead, Mass.: James J. H. Gregory), 1873, 1874; 212909 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 6)
    - Seed Catalog: Harlem Nursery. Catalogue of Fruit and Forest Trees, Flowering Shrubs, Evergreens, and Herbaceous Plants (New York: Michael Floy & Sons, 1832)., 212910 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 7)
    - Seed Catalog (Sawyer): Illustrated and Descriptive Catalogue of Choice and Select Flower and Garden Seeds (Portland, Me. W. C. Sawyer & Co., 1881)., 212914 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 8)
    - Seed Catalog (Terry): 1891 Seed Annual (Detroit: D. M. Terry & Co., 1891)., 212915 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 9)
    - Seed Catalog (Thorburn): Annual Catalogue High-Class Seeds (New York: J. M. Thorburn & Co., 1900)., 212916 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 10)
    - Seed Catalog: Van Bourgondien Bros. 1937 Spring Planting Guide, 212917 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 11)
    - Seed Catalog: R. A. van der Schoot (Holland), 212918 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 12)
    - Seed Catalog: Vick's Illustrated Floral Guide (Rochester, N.Y.: James Vick)., 1873, 1874; 212919 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 1)
    - Seed Catalog: Vick's Flower and Vegetable Garden (Rochester, N.Y.: James Vick)., [1880s?]; 212920 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 2)
    - Seed Catalog (Wayside): Hardy Herbaceous & Alpine Plants (Mentor, Ohio: Wayside Gardens Co., 1928)., 212921 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 3)
    - Three Hundred Years of Parks: A Timeline of New York City Park History (City of New York, Parks & Recreation), 1988; 213148 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 4)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number F128.64.A1 C32 1988.
    - United States Patent Office: Plant Patents (with illustrations), 1965; 212895 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 5)
      2548: Almond tree
      2549: Rose
      2550: Rose
      2551: Crepe Myrtle
      2552: Chrysanthemum
      2553: Rose
      2554: Chrysanthemum
      2555: Chrysanthemum
      2556: Redbud
      2557: Rose
      2558: Rose
      2559: Gladiolus
      2560: Gladiolus
      2561: Gladiolus
      2562: Gladiolus
      2563: Rose, Miniature
      2564: Plum
      2565: Rose
      2566: Ashtree
      2567: Fraxinius
      2568: Azalea
      2569: Rose
      2570: Rose
      2571: Plum
      2572: Cherry
      2576: Rose
      2577: Rose
      2578: Rose
      2579: Rose
    - Wild Flowers of Greece, n.d.; 212938 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 6)
      Portfolio of twelve loose prints, with captions in Greek.
      01. Anemone coronaria
      02. Vinca herbacea
      03. Crocus aureus
      04. Anemone blanda
      05. Iris attica
      06. Serapias vomeracea
      07. Cistus creticus
      08. Campanula spathulata 09. Lilium heldreichii
      10. Echinops graecus
      11. Dianthus diffusus
      12. Cyclamen graecum
    - [Book] Feasibility Study on the Creation of a City-Wide Plant Information Service, circa 1974; 212964 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 7)
    - [Book] Transactions of the Illinois State Horticultural Society, vols. 58-59, 1924-1925; 212962 (Offsite-box 82, Folder 1-2)
      The N-YHS Library holds other issues under call number F536 .I26.
    - [Book] The West Point Foundry Site, Cold Spring, Putnam County, New York (Ralph Brill Associates), 1979 November; 212967 (Offsite-box 82, Folder 3)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number F129.C648 R3.
    - [Book] The Gardens of Russell Page by Marina Schinz and Gabrielle van Zuylen (New York: Stewart, Tabori & Chang, 1991), 212961 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-108)
    - Botanical illustrations (loose prints & engravings) [Oversize], 1800s; 212855 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 2)
      Aquilegia canadensis
      Aralia spinosa (2)
      Arbutus unedo
      Arbutus uva ursi
      Cornus mascula
      Cornus paniculata
      Cornus sanguinea
      Cornus sericea
      Dillenia pentagyna
      Dionae muscipula
      Dodecotheon medea
      Duroia eriopila
      Egle
      Juglans cinerea
      Juglans nigra
      Lathyrus
      Lawsonia
      Ledum latifolium
      Ligusticum scoticum
      Ligustrum vulgare
      Lilium Martagon
      Limodorum
      Limonia
      Lonicera diervilla
      Lonicera media
      Lonicera nigra
      Lonicera periclymenum
      Lonicera sempervirens
      Lonicera symphoricarpos
      Lonicera xylosteum
      Lotus
      Malva
      Manisuris
      Maranta
      Marchantia
      Martynia
      Passiflora
      Pedicularis (2)
      Pelargonium (2)
      Periploca
      Periploca graeca
      Peucedanum
      Phalaris
      Phaseolus
      Phelipaea
      Philadelphus
      Philadelphus coronarius nanus
      Phillyrea
      Phlox (2)
      Phoenix
      Phyllanthus
      Physalis
      Pilularia
      Pimelaea
      Pinguicula
      Pinus (2)
      Pisum
      Pittosporum
      Plantago (2)
      Platanus orientalis
      Platanus orientalis acerifolia
      Plumbago
      Plumeria
      Poa
      Polemonium
      Polianthes
      Polygala
      Polypodium
      Polytrichum
      Pommerullia
      Populus
      Potamogeton
      Pontederia
      Portulaca
      Potentilla
      Primula var.
      Ptelea trifoliata
      Pyrola uniflora
      Ribes lacustre
    - "Exhibition of the N. Y. Horticultural Society at Clinton Hall, N. Y." Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper. [Oversize], 1856 July 5; 213183 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 3)
    - Foster, Laura Louise: Three signed botanical prints (on board) created for the American Rock Garden Society [Oversize], 1981; 213189 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 4)
      Claytonia caroliniana
      Cornus canadensis
      Iris verna
    - "General View of the Central Park, New York." Harper's Weekly. [Oversize], 1860 June 16; 213185 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 5)
    - Goulandris, Niki (artist): Twelve botanical prints. [Oversize], circa 1983; 213192 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 6)
      Gift to HSNY from Mrs. Goulandris, June 1983. Prints are copyright Goulandris Museum (Kifissia).
      01. Anemone pavonina var.
      02. Anemone pavonina var. purpureoviolacea
      03. Cyclamen graecum
      04. Cyclamen repandum
      05. Geranium macrorrhizum
      06. Glaucium flavum var. serpierii
      07. Hablerlea rhodeopensis
      08. Hypericum olympicum
      09. Lilium candidum
      10. Lilium chalcedonicum
      11. Rosa canina
      12. Symphyandra cretica
    - Lilies of Japan (West Orange, N.J.: Joseph Manda Co.) [Oversize], 212942 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 7)
    - Six Fern Botanicals (Victor Schrager and Martha Stewart Living) [Oversize], 1993; 213182 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 8)
      01. Japanese Painted Fern
      02. Trifid Holly Fern & Deceptive Wood Fern
      03. Southern Beech Fern & Eared Lady Fern
      04. Maidenhair Spleenwort, Ebony Spleenwort, Tatting Fern, Holly-Fern Woodsia & Rusty Woodsia
      05. Plumose Oak Fern & Robert's Oak Fern
      06. Evergreen Wood Fern & Woodland Fragine Fern
    - Williamson, Philemona (artist): Two watercolors--notated "Rikers Island" on back--for the July/August 1985 issue of HSNY's Garden. [Oversize], 213187 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 9)
    - Gourley, Josette (artist): "Vanda Hilo Princess 'Alice'" (limited edition print) [Oversize], 1980s; 213180 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 10)
    - Medicinal Plant Map of the United States (National Wholesale Druggists' Association) [Oversize], 1932 September; 213181 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 11)
    - Vanderlip Estate, Bedford, N.Y.: Gate renderings (2) by Luther Greene, landscape designer, and Roger Bartels, architect. [Oversize], 1983-1984; 213186 (Drawer Oversize-Large)
- Series VII. Audiovisual, 1964-2003; 212204; 11.96 Linear feet
  Series VII. Audiovisual, 1964-2003 is divided into the following subseries:
  Subseries VII.A. Audio Formats, 1968-1996
  Subseries VII.B. Moving Images, 1964-2003
  The Audiovisual series consists of video and audio recordings of activities related to The Horticultural Society of New York. These include meetings, lectures, flower shows, and other programs organized by HSNY. The annual Flower Shows from 1985 to 1995 are especially well-represented.
  The audio format includes thirty-three microcassettes; sevety-nine cassettes; three 6.5mm reels; six 7in. reels; and two 10in. reels. Content includes recordings of HSNY board meetings, lectures given at HSNY, clips from radio shows featuring HSNY programs, especially the flower shows, and radio spots advertising the flower shows.
  The moving image subseries contains fifty-two VHS tapes, five Betamax tapes, four 16 mm film reels, nine 35mm reels, and three CDs. The content consists of advertisements, announcements and news coverage of HSNY programs, mainly flower shows. Included are segments from the Today Show, 1992; Good Day New York, 1993; the Stephen Holt Show, 1991; NJ Cable; Brazilian TV; and a segment featuring Martha Stewart at the 1992 Flower Show. There are a number of copies of a 2003 CBS Good Morning feature on the Greenways Program called "Garden of Hope." Other tapes feature the Green Streets program; El Sol Brillente community garden; and the Garfield Park Conservatory.
  Access Restrictions
  N-YHS lacks playback equipment, so the material in Series VII. Audiovisual, 1964-2003, is restricted.
  - Subseries VII.A. Audio Formats, 1968-1996; 212264; 7.96 Linear feet
    33 meeting microcassettes; 56 meeting cassettes; 8 programs cassettes; 15 flower show cassettes; 3 6.5mm reels; 6 7in. reels; 2 10in. reels. Content includes recordings of HSNY board meetings, lectures given at HSNY, clips from radio shows featuring HSNY programs, especially the flower shows, and radio spots advertising the flower shows.
    - Flower Shows: cassettes, 1970-1997; 212316 (Offsite-box 90, Box 66)
    - Flower Shows: tape reels, 1984-1987; 212544 (Offsite-box 90, Box 67)
    - Flower Shows: tape reels, 1990-1991; 212380 (Offsite-box 110, Box FF-9)
    - HSNY Meetings: microcassettes, 1999-2004; 212268 (Offsite-box 90, Box 68)
    - HSNY Meetings: cassettes, 1981-1992; 212269 (Offsite-box 91, Box 69)
    - HSNY Meetings: cassettes, 1993-1995; 212271 (Offsite-box 91, Box 70)
    - HSNY Meetings: cassettes, 1996; 212280 (Offsite-box 91, Box 71)
    - HSNY Meetings: tape reel, 1968; 212476 (Offsite-box 110, Box FF-10)
    - Programs and lectures: cassettes, 1973-1996; 212283 (Offsite-box 91, Box 72)
    - Programs and lectures: reel, undated; 212542 (Offsite-box 110, Box FF-10)
    - Unidentified: tape reels, u.d.; 212471 (Offsite-box 110, Box FF-10)
  - Subseries VII.B. Moving Images, 1964-2003; 212265; 4 Linear feet
    This subseries contains fifty-two VHS tapes, five Betamax tapes, four 16 mm film reels, nine 35mm reels, and three CDs. The content consists of advertisements, announcements and news coverage of HSNY programs, mainly flower shows. Included are segments from the Today Show, 1992; Good Day New York, 1993; the Stephen Holt Show, 1991; NJ Cable; Brazilian TV; and a segment featuring Martha Stewart at the 1992 Flower Show. There are a number of copies of a 2003 CBS Good Morning feature on the Greenways Program called "Garden of Hope." Other tapes feature the Green Streets program; El Sol Brillente community garden; and the Garfield Park Conservatory 2002.
    - Flower Shows: Betamax tapes, 1985; 212516 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Flower Shows: VHS tapes, 1990-1991; 212673 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Flower Shows: film reels (35 mm), 1987-1991; 212672 (Offsite-box 73)
    - Flower Shows: film reels (16 mm), 1964-1982; 212675 (Offsite-box 74)
    - Flower Shows: VHS tapes, 1992-1995; 212674 (Offsite-box 75)
    - Programs and lectures: VHS tapes, 1982-2003; 212517 (Offsite-box 76)
    - Programs and lectures: Compact discs, 1990s; 212682 (Offsite-box 76)
- Series VIII. Reference Files, 1850-2005; 211445; 8 Linear feet
  Series VIII. Reference Files, 1850-2005 is divided into the following subseries:
  Subseries VIII.A. People, 1910-2009
  Subseries VIII.B. Subjects, 1850-2006
  This series consists of the reference files maintained by the Horticultural Society of NY. The series is divided into two main topics: People and Subjects. Each topic is arranged alphabetically. The files include images, journal articles, newspaper clippings, brochures, programs, and biographies related to people and subjects of interest to the staff of the HSNY.
  People include board members and donors, as well as botanists and plant scientists such as Henry Svenson, and landscape architects such as Agnes Selkirk Clark.
  Subjects include topics such as Central Park, community gardens, garden design, greenhouses, landscape architecture, various plant species, and a wide assortment of other subjects.
  - Subseries VIII.A. People, 1910-2009; 213270; 3 Linear feet
    - People: A, 1930-2007; 211446 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 1)
      Abel, Mrs. Murray
      Allen, Charles
      Allport, Alexander
      Appell, Scott
      Auchincloss Family
    - People: B (1 of 5), 1910-2009; 211737 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 2)
      Bailey, Liberty
      Baker, Richard
      Barr, William
      Barron, Leonard
      Barton, Benjamin
    - People: B (2 of 5), 1910-2009; 213509 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 3)
      Bartram, John
      Bauman, Dina
      Bechtel, Edwin
    - People: B (3 of 5), 1910-2009; 213510 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 4)
      Beineke, Elizabeth
      Belcher, Mrs. Benjamin
      Benenson, Sharen
      Benjamin, Herta
      Berkowitz, Mortimer
      Berns, Frank
      Bertron, Samuel
      Blackburn, Benjamin
      Board, current bios
    - People: B (4 of 5), 1910-2009; 213511 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 5)
      Brilmayer, Bernice
      Britton, Elizabeth
      Britton, Nathaniel
      Brown, Addison
      Bogart, Ted
      Bogart, Walter
      Bonham, Frederick
      Booke, Ruth
      Boyd, James
    - People: B (5 of 5), 1910-2009; 213512 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 6)
      Bryant, William Cullen
      Buck, Leonard
      Bucknall, Ann
      Burbank, Luther
      Burpee, W. Atlee
      Bush-Brown, Louise
    - People: C (1 of 4), 1920-2008; 211796 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 7)
      Cabot, Francis
      Canning, John
      Caplan, Ira
      Carle, George
      Carnegie, Mrs. Andrew
      Cary, Mrs. William
      Chatto, Beth
      Cholaris, Betty
    - People: C (2 of 4), 1920-2008; 213514 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 8)
      Christiansen, Emil
      Christman, W. F.
      Clark, Agnes Selkirk
      Clark, Elizabeth
      Clark, George
      Clark, James
      Clark, Mrs. Jay
      Clark, Phil
      Clark, Samuel
      Clark, Walter
      Clarke, Gilmore
      Clarkson, Edward
      Clarkson, Rosetta
      Clavey, F. D.
      Clements, Julia
      Clibran, William
      Cloud, K.M.P.
      Cloudsley, J. Rowland
      Cobbett, William
      Cocchi, Antonio
      Cockayne, L.
    - People: C (3 of 4), 1920-2008; 213515 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 9)
      Coe, Michael
      Coe, William
      Coffin, Marian
      Coffin, Peter
    - People: C (4 of 4), 1920-2008; 213516 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 10)
      Coggan, S. W.
      Colden, Jane
      Cole, Nelson
      Cole, W.B.
      Colflesh, J. William
      Collinson, Peter
      Colman, Jeremiah
      Comley, George
      Conklin, Everett
      Corning, Mrs. Erastus
      Cottle, Donald
      Cran, Marian
      Cronquist, Arthur
      Cromwell, James
      Cross, Mrs. W. Redmond
    - People: D (1 of 2), 1920-1999; 211801 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 11)
      D'Agostino, Nicholas
      Daverheim, Mel
      Deitz, Paula
      De La Mare, A.T.
      Dean, Ruth
      Delano, William
      Desmond, Thomas
      Dickson, Alex
      Deitz, Fordyce
      Dorman, Caroline
      Doscher, Alice
      Douglas, Lucille
    - People: D (2 of 2), 1920-1999; 213519 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 12)
      Dowden, Anne
      Downer, Henry
      Downing, Andrew J.
      Duke, Doris
      Duncan, William
      Dupont, Henry
      Dupont, Pierre
    - People: E, 1935-2003; 211807 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 13)
      Eaton, Jerome
      Edison, Thomas
      Ekstrom, Nicolas
      Elbert, George
      Elwes, Mary
      Emerson, Ralph Waldo
      Epstein, Harold
      Esson, James
    - People: F, 1920-2000; 211808 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 14)
      Farnham, Richard
      Farrand, Beatrix
      Farrer, Reginald
      Favretti, RJ
      Ferriday, Eliza
      Field, Marshall
      Fox, Helen
      Free, Montague
      Freund, Karl
      Friedericksen, Ernest
      Fry, Gladys
    - People: G (1 of 3), 1920-2000; 211809 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 1)
      Gaddis, Jane
      Gaden, Eileen
      Gager, C. Stuart
      Galfano, Rose
      Gambee, Eleanor
      Garmey, Jane
      Gibson, Constance
      Gillies, George
      Gish, Lillian
    - People: G (2 of 3), 1920-2000; 213520 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 2)
      Greene, Luther
      Goldman, Amy
    - People: G (3 of 3), 1920-2000; 213521 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 3)
      Gonzales, Ricardo
      Gottscho, Samuel
      Graf, Alfred
      Greenwood, Leslie
      Grimaldi, Marie
      Guest, C.Z.
      Gunnison, Mrs. R.R.
    - People: H (1 of 3), 1920-2000; 211811 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 4)
      Hall, Elizabeth
      Harding, Charles
      Harrington, David
    - People: H (2 of 3), 1920-2000; 213522 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 5)
      Haupt, Enid
      Havemeyer, Theodore
      Hay, Clarence
      Hecht, Fae
      Hecht, George
      Hellyer, Arthur
      Henderson, Peter
    - People: H (3 of 3), 1920-2000; 213523 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 6)
      Herman, Jay
      Hewitt, Mattie Edwards
      Hexamer, F.M.
      Hicks
      Hill, Fanny
      Hill, May
      Hines, Mrs. Walter
      Hines, Linda
      Hodgkins, Ann
      Hosack, David
      Hubbard, Robert
      Hudes, Harry
      Hull, Olive
    - People: I-J, 1963-1999; 211812 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 7)
      Iselin, W.E.
      Jack, James
      Jekyll, Gertrude
      Johnston, Vernon
    - People: K, 1925-1999; 211813 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 8)
      Kaupman, Dorothy
      Kazimiroff, Theodore
      Kean, Mrs. H.F.
      Kennedy, Margaret
      Kerr, Jessica
      King, Mrs. Francis
      Knapp, Mrs. Arthur
      Kottmiller
    - People: L (1 of 2), 1910-2000; 211814 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 9)
      Lacerte, Susan
      Laughlin, Cynthia
      Lawrence, William
      Lee, Frederic
      Lee, Patti
      Lees, Carlton
      Legendre, Jacques
      Lemoine, Victor
      Levick, Edwin
      Levison, J.J.
      Levy, Mrs. Louis
      Lewis, Clarence
      Lewisohn, Adolph
      Lindenmeyr, Henry
      Linnaeus, Carolus
    - People: L (2 of 2), 1910-2000; 213526 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 10)
      Lockwood, Netta
      Lockwood, Mrs. William
    - People: M, 1925-2000; 211816 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 11)
      Macy, V. Everett
      Manda, Edward
      Manda, Joseph
      Margolis, Barbara
      Martin, John
      Marx, Roberto
      May, Harry
      Maynard, Walter
      Midler, Bette
      Miner, Frances
      Mitchell, Henry
      Moeller, William
      Moore, Clement
    - People: N-O, 1920-2005; 211817 (Offsite-box 45, Folder 12)
      Nash, George
      Newbold, Frederic
      Nordheden, Albert
      North, Marianne
      Otis, Denise
    - People: P (1 of 2), 1919-2000; 211819 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 1)
      Pardue, Larry
      Parsons, Samuel
      Payne, Frederick
      Peruggi, Regina
      Peterson, Elizabeth
      Pierson, F.R.
      Place, Mrs. Herman
      Platt, Charles
      Plumier, Charles
    - People: P (2 of 2), 1919-2000; 213642 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 2)
      Pollan, Michael
      Powell, George
      Powell, Tom
      Pratt, George
      Pratt, Mrs. Harold
      Pratt, Helen
      Prince, William
      Pyle, Robert
    - People: R, 1930-1999; 211821 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 3)
      Rae, Robert
      Ragionieri, Attillo
      Raver, Anne
      Redoute, Pierre
      Reed, Henry
      Rehm, Hans
      Rehman, Elsa
      Robinson, William
      Rodman, William
      Roebling, Mrs. John A.
      Roehrs, Julius
      Rudolph, Emanuel
    - People: S (1 of 4), 1910-2000; 211822 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 4)
      Sailer, Anthony
      Sanders, Margaret
      Sawin, Mrs. Melvin
      Schlegel, George
      Scholtz, Elizabeth
      Schutz, Paul
      Scott, Robert
      Serlin, Kate
      Scheepers, John
      Schling, Max
      Sheil, Maeve
    - People: S (2 of 4), 1910-2000; 213527 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 5)
      Sheppard, Arthur
      Shipman, Ellen
      Sloan, Samuel
      Smith, Anthony
      Smith, Georgiana
      Smith, Mary Riley
      Smith, Suzette
      Smith, William
      Smithers, Peter
      Spade, Kate
    - People: S (3 of 4), 1910-2000; 213528 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 6)
      Spingarn, J.E.
      Steichen, Edward
      Stoltz, Raymond
      Stones, Margaret
    - People: S (4 of 4), 1910-2000; 213529 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 7)
      Stout, Arlow
      Strang, Elizabeth
      Stuart, James
      Stufano, Marco
      Svenson, Henry
    - People: T, 1920-2000; 211823 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 8)
      Tabor, Grace
      Taloumis, G.
      Thaxter, Celia
      Thorne, Samuel
      Tiffany, Louis
      Tomberlaine, Verdalee
      Torrey, John
      Totty, Charles
      Tozer, Elizabeth
      Trowbridge, Mrs. Cecil
    - People: V, 1935-2001; 211824 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 9)
      Verey, Rosemary
      Vester, Bertha
      Voors, H.Y.
    - People: W (1 of 2), 1920-2000; 211826 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 10)
      Walcott, Mary
      Weber, Nelva
      Webster, Charles
      Weiler, Richard
      Wharton, Edith
      Wheeler, Wilfred
      Wilder, Louise
      White, C.R.
    - People: W (2 of 2), 1920-2000; 213530 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 11)
      White, Somers
      Whitney, Mrs. Payne
      Wilson, Ernest
      Wood, James
      Woodburn, Elizabeth
      Wright, Richardson
    - People: Y-Z, 1930-2000; 211827 (Offsite-box 46, Folder 12)
      York, Lewis
      Young, John
      Zabar, Abbie
      Zinsser, Barbara
  - Subseries VIII.B. Subjects, 1850-2006; 213271; 5 Linear feet
    - Subjects: A, 1920-1984; 211828 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 1)
      Arbors
      Atriums
    - Subjects: B (1 of 4), 1930-2000; 211830 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 2)
      Banks and Slopes
      Battery Park City
      Beans
    - Subjects: B (2 of 4), 1930-2000; 213531 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 3)
      Biblical Garden, St. John the Divine
      Biblical plants
    - Subjects: B (3 of 4), 1930-2000; 213532 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 4)
      Bonsai
      Botanic art
    - Subjects: B (4 of 4), 1930-2000; 213533 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 5)
      Bryant Park
      Brooklyn Botanic Garden
    - Subjects: C (1 of 11), 1850-2000; 211831 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 6)
      Catalogues: seeds and nurseries
    - Subjects: C (2 of 11), 1850-2000; 213535 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 7)
      Central Park
      Central Park Conservancy
    - Subjects: C (3 of 11), 1850-2000; 213536 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 8)
      Central Park Conservancy (continued)
    - Subjects: C (4 of 11), 1850-2000; 213537 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 9)
      Children's gardens
      China: gardens
    - Subjects: C (5 of 11), 1850-2000; 213538 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 10)
      Christmas
      Cocoa
    - Subjects: C (6 of 11), 1850-2000; 213539 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 11)
      Coffee
      Cold frames
    - Subjects: C (7 of 11), 1850-2000; 213540 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 1)
      Colonial gardens
      Community gardens
    - Subjects: C (8 of 11), 1850-2000; 213541 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 2)
      Community gardens (continued)
    - Subjects: C (9 of 11), 1850-2000; 213542 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 3)